<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://davidauble.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://davidauble.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-02-27T12:52:36-05:00</updated><id>https://davidauble.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Indianapolis Web Developer</title><subtitle>Indianapolis-based marketing professional with experience in working with enterprise companies, solving complex problems and visualizing big data.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">David Auble, Manager</title><link href="https://davidauble.com/2020/09/06/new-job-promotion.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="David Auble, Manager" /><published>2020-09-06T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-09-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://davidauble.com/2020/09/06/new-job-promotion</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://davidauble.com/2020/09/06/new-job-promotion.html">&lt;p&gt;It’s been no secret that I’ve been working towards finishing my MBA in Finance. I am on track to graduate this coming December and am excited to have not only completed the two year program, but for what lies ahead. I’ve been wanting to get into managment and knew this was one of the best ways to learn how to become a manager and leader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few months back, I left the marketing world in pursuit of something more challenging. Marketing has been in my DNA since my first exposure in 2011, and will always hold a place dear to me, as I love brand generation, fast-paced work environments, and the variety of projects found in typical marketing agencies. The fresh atmosphere of new talent reignites my passion for helping connect people with their dreams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this switch, I joined a product development team – a team that builds extended reality (XR) applications and is on the forefront of innovation. We are building virtual environments utilizing equipment such as the Microsoft Hololens to assist our clients in their quest for changing career paths. We take advantage of cloud technologies such as the IBM Watson Artifical Intelligence system, Microsoft Azure speech recognition, and many others, to help close the gap between “using” technology and having technology become part of daily life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was approached recently about my career goals and what I wanted to do in the near future. After expressing my desire to apply what I’ve been learning with my MBA, I was asked if I was interested in managment and helping mentor a team of developers. Being no stranger to jumping head-first out of my comfort zone, I jumped on this opportunity and began talks of what a new role would look like, and how to best help my current team thrive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward a few months and it’s become official: I have now achieved one of my five-year goals - to lead a team of developers and be responsible for their development and growth. I am beyond excited for this new challenge. It will require a lot of work, a lot of time learning and getting to know my team, and will mistakes will be made. However, I learn quickly and am determined to be an invaluable leader on the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have never had a bad boss. I stand by this statement. I have been given many opportunities to show leadership and have acquired a vast amount of knowledge during my professional tenure. Each boss has taught me invaluable lessons on mentoring, leadership, managment, and delegation. For that, I am grateful to each of my former bosses and managers. Thank you. You have helped shape me and prepare me for what lies ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, with that, I am excited this new adventure and to dive head-first into this new role. Thank you to all who have helped make this dream a reality.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>dauble</name></author><summary type="html">It’s been no secret that I’ve been working towards finishing my MBA in Finance. I am on track to graduate this coming December and am excited to have not only completed the two year program, but for what lies ahead. I’ve been wanting to get into managment and knew this was one of the best ways to learn how to become a manager and leader.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://davidauble.com/assets/images/posts/david-auble-manager.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://davidauble.com/assets/images/posts/david-auble-manager.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Targeting Internet Explorer with CSS Media Queries</title><link href="https://davidauble.com/2020/05/05/targeting-internet-explorer-with-css-media-queries.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Targeting Internet Explorer with CSS Media Queries" /><published>2020-05-05T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-05-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://davidauble.com/2020/05/05/targeting-internet-explorer-with-css-media-queries</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://davidauble.com/2020/05/05/targeting-internet-explorer-with-css-media-queries.html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve been using CSS Grid and Flexbox for a little while now for different parts of websites. They work in all modern browsers and it saves me time from having to put together cheap hacks. One of the caveats to using Grid though is that older browsers such as IE10 and 11 don’t fully support it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a recent build I had a section with four small boxes and a title. Normally I’d use Bootstrap’s &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.col-md-3&lt;/code&gt; class, but since I am moving away from Bootstrap alltogether, I was faced with another challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typically I support browsers back two versions, so I’m still supporting IE10/11. Although many of Grid/Flexbox’s capabilities work, there are some legacy specs that need to be used for them to work properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most useful though is an IE-only media query, so it doesn’t break other styles. Take a look:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;@media all and (-ms-high-contrast: none), (-ms-high-contrast: active) {
 /* IE specific queries here */
}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s it! When using this media query, it is important to note you can’t simply but styles in the brackets. You must define the class and then styles. Below is a sample of my implemenation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;@media all and (-ms-high-contrast: none), (-ms-high-contrast: active) {
 .callout__container {
   margin: 0 1em;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&amp;amp;:first-of-type {
     margin: 0 1em 0 0;
   }&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&amp;amp;:last-of-type {
     margin: 0 0 0 1em;
   }
 }
}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this helps!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>dauble</name></author><category term="css" /><category term="ie" /><category term="internet explorer" /><summary type="html">I’ve been using CSS Grid and Flexbox for a little while now for different parts of websites. They work in all modern browsers and it saves me time from having to put together cheap hacks. One of the caveats to using Grid though is that older browsers such as IE10 and 11 don’t fully support it.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://davidauble.com/assets/images/posts/ie-11-background.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://davidauble.com/assets/images/posts/ie-11-background.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Common WordPress Helper Functions</title><link href="https://davidauble.com/2020/04/29/common-wordpress-helper-functions.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Common WordPress Helper Functions" /><published>2020-04-29T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-04-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://davidauble.com/2020/04/29/common-wordpress-helper-functions</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://davidauble.com/2020/04/29/common-wordpress-helper-functions.html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve used WordPress almost daily for the past six years and thought it’d be time to share some of my more commonly used functions WordPress has built in to the framework. Below is a list of the functions I use frequently on most of the sites I build.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;wp_is_mobile&quot;&gt;wp_is_mobile()&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;wp_is_mobile()&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This function detects if someone is using a mobile device or not. Extremely handy for when you want certain features (such as tracking scripts, chat applications, etc) to not appear when users are using mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;is_user_logged_in&quot;&gt;is_user_logged_in()&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;is_user_logged_in()&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it sounds, this checks to see if the current user is logged in or not. Handy little script for turning off tracking scripts or other non-essential parts when users are logged in. This can also be used to protect content areas that require membership roles to view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;is_page_template&quot;&gt;is_page_template()&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;is_page_template(‘template-sample.php’)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;is_front_page&quot;&gt;is_front_page()&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;is_front_page()&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This function simply checks to see if the current page is set as the Front Page in WordPress. This page is set under Settings -&amp;gt; Reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;is_home&quot;&gt;is_home()&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;is_home()&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This function simply checks to see if the current page is set as the Posts Page in WordPress. This page is set under Settings -&amp;gt; Reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;wp_reset_postdata&quot;&gt;wp_reset_postdata()&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;wp_reset_postdata()&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When using custom loops, this resets the Posts loop so the rest of the page will render properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;restore_current_blog&quot;&gt;restore_current_blog()&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;restore_current_blog(1)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When working with a multisite setup, this allows you to change which blog to grab content. Pass in the Site ID as an arugment to load that site’s content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;get_template_part&quot;&gt;get_template_part()&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;get_template_part(‘included-template.php’)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This functions like an include for WordPress. Simple pass in the PHP template filename as an argument.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bloginfo&quot;&gt;bloginfo()&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;bloginfo(‘url’)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the more useful functions, this enables you to grab various info about the WordPress site. Some arguments I use frequently are &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;url&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;template_directory&lt;/code&gt;. These return the site’s URL and theme path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information on these functions and more, visit the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.wordpress.org/reference/functions/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;WordPress Developer reference&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>dauble</name></author><category term="wordpress" /><category term="php" /><summary type="html">I’ve used WordPress almost daily for the past six years and thought it’d be time to share some of my more commonly used functions WordPress has built in to the framework. Below is a list of the functions I use frequently on most of the sites I build.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://davidauble.com/assets/images/posts/common-wordpress-functions.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://davidauble.com/assets/images/posts/common-wordpress-functions.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Getting Jekyll Running on Windows 10 x64</title><link href="https://davidauble.com/2020/04/19/jekyll-on-windows.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Getting Jekyll Running on Windows 10 x64" /><published>2020-04-19T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-04-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://davidauble.com/2020/04/19/jekyll-on-windows</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://davidauble.com/2020/04/19/jekyll-on-windows.html">&lt;p&gt;I use a Mac and a PC equally and want to be able to work on projects regardless of development environment. As mentioned &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/04/10/2020-blog-update.html&quot;&gt;previously&lt;/a&gt;, I’ve converted my site over to Jekyll. It works well on both systems, but when I went to install it on my PC, I ran into the following issue:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Unable to load the EventMachine C extension; To use the pure-ruby reactor, require ‘em/pure_ruby’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Puzzled, I scoured Google and StackOverflow and came up empty. I thought &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/30682575/unable-to-load-the-eventmachine-c-extension-to-use-the-pure-ruby-reactor&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this post on StackOverflow&lt;/a&gt; would help get me there, but I ended up back at the same spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a while, I finally started looking into different flags I could use to run with these commands. I finally figured out a solution - force the uninstall of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;eventmachine&lt;/code&gt; and reinstall it using the Ruby platform. Voila! All set!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the final steps I used to fix this problem:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;bundle&lt;br /&gt;
gem uninstall eventmachine –force&lt;br /&gt;
gem install eventmachine –platform ruby&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>dauble</name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="command line" /><summary type="html">I use a Mac and a PC equally and want to be able to work on projects regardless of development environment. As mentioned previously, I’ve converted my site over to Jekyll. It works well on both systems, but when I went to install it on my PC, I ran into the following issue:</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://davidauble.com/assets/images/posts/page-speed-insights.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://davidauble.com/assets/images/posts/page-speed-insights.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Edit Robots.txt with WordPress and Yoast</title><link href="https://davidauble.com/2020/04/14/edit-robots-txt-wordpress-yoast.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Edit Robots.txt with WordPress and Yoast" /><published>2020-04-14T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-04-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://davidauble.com/2020/04/14/edit-robots-txt-wordpress-yoast</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://davidauble.com/2020/04/14/edit-robots-txt-wordpress-yoast.html">&lt;p&gt;An interesting project came my way this week at work and took some digging to resolve. Each website utilizes a file called a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;robots.txt&lt;/code&gt; file that helps point search engine bots what areas of your site to crawl and which to ignore. This helps the bots crawl your site and help it appear on search engines and can impact your search rankings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve been using Yoast SEO for our primary SEO plugin on all of our sites for quite some time and albeit it buggy and &lt;a href=&quot;https://yoast.com/media-attachment-urls/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;catastrophic at times&lt;/a&gt;, however for the most part, it is the best SEO plugin available for WordPress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I was given the task to update the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;robots.txt&lt;/code&gt; file on each site to include a link to the sitemap.xml file, generated by Yoast. I immediately thought to check the site’s primary directory, but didn’t see a text file in that location. I then checked the built-in file editor in WordPress, but came up blank, as it only allowed me to edit template files. Hmm..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, for some background, each of our websites is set up using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.org/support/article/glossary/#multisite&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Multisite&lt;/a&gt; feature in WordPress. Each site in the network has its own set of options with Yoast and has an area to update the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;robots.txt&lt;/code&gt;. However, that option has been removed and I wasn’t able to find which version of Yoast removed that option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, after digging much further, I was able to find that in the Network Admin area, another Yoast Options page exists. From here, you have the option to click &lt;em&gt;Edit Files&lt;/em&gt;, which allows you to generate and modify the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;robots.txt&lt;/code&gt; file from within WordPress. Finally! Below are the steps I took to solve this problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click on Network Admin -&amp;gt; Dashboard&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/network-admin.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Clicking on Network Admin, followed by Dashboard link&quot; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hover over the Yoast SEO options and click Edit Files&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/seo-edit-files.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Click on Yoast SEO, Edit Files&quot; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Edit robots.txt&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/edit-robots.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Edit robots.txt text input&quot; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt; If a robots.txt file does not exist, in the current verion of WordPress, 5.4, clicking the “Generate robots.txt” button will redirect you to a page that has HTML markup not being rendered. Simply click the browser’s back button and refresh the page. You will then see the edit text area as seen above.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>dauble</name></author><category term="wordpress" /><category term="apache" /><category term="iis" /><category term="seo" /><summary type="html">An interesting project came my way this week at work and took some digging to resolve. Each website utilizes a file called a robots.txt file that helps point search engine bots what areas of your site to crawl and which to ignore. This helps the bots crawl your site and help it appear on search engines and can impact your search rankings.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://davidauble.com/assets/images/posts/robots.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://davidauble.com/assets/images/posts/robots.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">2020 Blog Update</title><link href="https://davidauble.com/2020/04/10/2020-blog-update.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2020 Blog Update" /><published>2020-04-10T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-04-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://davidauble.com/2020/04/10/2020-blog-update</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://davidauble.com/2020/04/10/2020-blog-update.html">&lt;p&gt;It’s been nearly a year since I’ve had any updates to this site other than a couple of logos here and there. I’ve been overloaded between my full-time job, being a full-time MBA student, and helping raise my first child with my wife. The good news is life has been going well, I’ve just been extremely busy. We haven’t been able to travel due to my classes and projects, but have managed to get away for a couple weekends here and there to visit family and friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have, however, been paying particularly close attention to the performance side of websites with my current job. I’ve been researching what goes into web page performance and have found a combination of several things. For many years now I’ve wanted to get away from using a CMS and WordPress for my personal site, as it offers too much and I simply don’t use most of its features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, I’ve switched to a static site generator, &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. Jekyll is a static site generator and uses a combination of Markdown, Liquid, HTML, CSS to build out websites. It is designed for bloggers who want a simple site. It can be run on any web host, with many users hosting their sites on GitHub Pages. I chose not to do that, as I have other projects and need a web host.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, I love Jekyll. It’s quick to learn, and requires minimal effort to create a new post. Best of all, it allows you to build a site and run it locally without having to have a virtual server running - it creates one for you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing worth mentioning - this year, it is my goal to completely move away from Bootstrap and roll my own scaffolding. I’ve been working with &lt;a href=&quot;https://css-tricks.com/snippets/css/complete-guide-grid/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CSS Grid&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://css-tricks.com/snippets/css/a-guide-to-flexbox/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Flexbox&lt;/a&gt; more and more lately, pushing myself to keep up with the times. I definitely am liking the benefits, and have a ways to go before I’m as comfortable with them as other languages. I’ll get there. Stay tuned, as I’m sure I’ll write about caveats I find along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, that’s pretty much it for now. While spending quite a bit of time inside due to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coronavirus_disease_2019&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;COVID-19&lt;/a&gt;, I’ve been able to slow down and get to some projects that have been on the backburner for a while. It feels great to accomplish projects, regardless of size. Stay safe out there, everyone! Wear a mask, and keep up with the social distancing! It does work, and together, let’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/FlattenTheCurve&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;#flattenthecurve&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>dauble</name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">It’s been nearly a year since I’ve had any updates to this site other than a couple of logos here and there. I’ve been overloaded between my full-time job, being a full-time MBA student, and helping raise my first child with my wife. The good news is life has been going well, I’ve just been extremely busy. We haven’t been able to travel due to my classes and projects, but have managed to get away for a couple weekends here and there to visit family and friends.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://davidauble.com/assets/images/posts/2020-blog-update.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://davidauble.com/assets/images/posts/2020-blog-update.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Improving WordPress Search Results with Relevanssi</title><link href="https://davidauble.com/2019/03/05/improving-wordpress-search-results-with-relevanssi.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Improving WordPress Search Results with Relevanssi" /><published>2019-03-05T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-03-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://davidauble.com/2019/03/05/improving-wordpress-search-results-with-relevanssi</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://davidauble.com/2019/03/05/improving-wordpress-search-results-with-relevanssi.html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve been managing 17 WordPress sites for the past few years and one thing I’ve noticed is the default search built into WordPress isn’t flexible and doesn’t always return the most accurate results. I use Advanced Custom Fields heavily for each of the sites and have noticed the default search doesn’t search into these fields; it only searches titles and what’s in the page’s main content box. Since most of the pages on our sites don’t use those, I needed to find a better option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I looked into managed search solutions such as Algolia and Elasticsearch, but for my needs, those went above and beyond, not to mention were costly. I looked at other WordPress plugins, but since I use the Multisite feature on each site, almost none of the plugins were able to search across the WordPress network. Then I came across &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.relevanssi.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Relevanssi&lt;/a&gt;. Relevanssi offers two versions, free and paid, and promises to look into ACF fields and give more flexibility on searches. It allows me to add custom weights to titles, body fields, custom post types, add synonyms for related words, offers “Did you mean ___?” functionality and best of all, searches across a WordPress network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After playing around with several settings, I was able to get the search results displaying nearly how I wanted. My two criteria were to have Pages appear above Posts, and to only display Posts newer than the previous two years. To do this though, I had to add some additional customization to my functions.php file. Luckily, the Relevanssi documentation is extremely helpful and detailed, plus the plugin author replies to each comment on support document pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s what I ended up with in my functions.php file to display Pages above Posts, then return results newer than two years:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
add_filter('relevanssi_hits_filter', 'products_first');
  function products_first($hits) {
    $types = array();

    $types['page'] = array();
    $types['post'] = array();

    // Split the post types in array $types
    if (!empty($hits)) {
      foreach ($hits[0] as $hit) {

        $date_cutoff = date('Y-m-d h:i:s', strtotime('-2 years'));
        if($hit-&amp;gt;post_date &amp;gt; $date_cutoff &amp;amp;&amp;amp; $hit-&amp;gt;post_type == 'post') {
          array_push($types[$hit-&amp;gt;post_type], $hit);
        }

        if($hit-&amp;gt;post_type == 'page') {
          array_push($types[$hit-&amp;gt;post_type], $hit);
        }
      }
    }

    // Merge back to $hits in the desired order
    $hits[0] = array_merge($types['page'], $types['post']);
    return $hits;
  }
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also noticed that sometimes, plural versions of words weren’t displaying properly either. Sometimes searching for “car” would return different results than “cars.” To get around this, I added a bit more code, found directly from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.relevanssi.com/knowledge-base/simple-french-plurals/&quot;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;add_filter( 'relevanssi_stemmer', 'relevanssi_french_plural_stemmer' );
    function relevanssi_french_plural_stemmer( $term ) {
      $len  = strlen( $term );
      $end1 = substr( $term, -1, 1 );

      if ( 's' === $end1 &amp;amp;&amp;amp; $len &amp;gt; 3 ) {
        $term = substr( $term, 0, -1 );
      } elseif ( 'x' === $end1 &amp;amp;&amp;amp; $len &amp;gt; 3 ) {
        $term = substr( $term, 0, -1 );
      }

      return $term;
    }&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I couldn’t be happier with this plugin and hope it solves any problems you might have.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>dauble</name></author><category term="wordpress" /><category term="relevanssi" /><category term="php" /><summary type="html">I’ve been managing 17 WordPress sites for the past few years and one thing I’ve noticed is the default search built into WordPress isn’t flexible and doesn’t always return the most accurate results. I use Advanced Custom Fields heavily for each of the sites and have noticed the default search doesn’t search into these fields; it only searches titles and what’s in the page’s main content box. Since most of the pages on our sites don’t use those, I needed to find a better option.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://davidauble.com/assets/images/posts/relevanssi-search.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://davidauble.com/assets/images/posts/relevanssi-search.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Change the WordPress Admin Login Logo</title><link href="https://davidauble.com/2019/01/24/how-to-change-the-wordpress-admin-login-logo.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Change the WordPress Admin Login Logo" /><published>2019-01-24T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-01-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://davidauble.com/2019/01/24/how-to-change-the-wordpress-admin-login-logo</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://davidauble.com/2019/01/24/how-to-change-the-wordpress-admin-login-logo.html">&lt;p&gt;Over the years I’ve had to search for tons of small snippets for WordPress to do simple tasks. This is another one of those little snippets. One of the final little touches I like to do before launching a website over to a client is to override the default WordPress logo with their logo on the WordPress login splash screen. It’s a simple trick and can be done with the code below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;// load in admin styles
                function admin_style() {
                  wp_enqueue_style('admin-styles', get_template_directory_uri().'/admin.css');
                }
                add_action('admin_enqueue_scripts', 'admin_style');&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, you’ll need to simply overwrite the default WordPress styling:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;body .login h1 a {
                  background-image: url('path/to/the-logo.png');
                }&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this helps!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>dauble</name></author><category term="wordpress" /><category term="php" /><summary type="html">Over the years I’ve had to search for tons of small snippets for WordPress to do simple tasks. This is another one of those little snippets. One of the final little touches I like to do before launching a website over to a client is to override the default WordPress logo with their logo on the WordPress login splash screen. It’s a simple trick and can be done with the code below.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://davidauble.com/assets/images/posts/wp-walker.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://davidauble.com/assets/images/posts/wp-walker.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Using PHP to Determine Server Protocol</title><link href="https://davidauble.com/2018/11/05/using-php-to-determine-server-protocol.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Using PHP to Determine Server Protocol" /><published>2018-11-05T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-11-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://davidauble.com/2018/11/05/using-php-to-determine-server-protocol</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://davidauble.com/2018/11/05/using-php-to-determine-server-protocol.html">&lt;p&gt;For various projects I build, I always have three environments: local, staging and production. On my staging and production environments, I have HTTPS enabled, but to keep things simple, I never set up HTTPS on my local environment. A lot of sites I build require forms that redirect the user to a thank you page, once the data is sent and processed to Salesforce. The redirect though requires an absolute path, so I cannot use something like “/contact/thank-you/”. To accomplish this, I use this simple line in PHP to display the appropriate protocol, regardless of dev environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;$protocol = (!empty($_SERVER['HTTPS']) &amp;amp;&amp;amp; $_SERVER['HTTPS'] !== 'off' || $_SERVER['SERVER_PORT'] == 443) ? &quot;https://&quot; : &quot;http://&quot;;
                $page_url = $protocol . $_SERVER[&quot;SERVER_NAME&quot;] . $_SERVER[&quot;REQUEST_URI&quot;];&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, in the form’s retURL hidden input, I echo out the page URL:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;input type=&quot;text&quot; name=&quot;00NC00000067ygp&quot; id=&quot;00NC00000067ygp&quot; value=&quot;&amp;lt;?php echo $page_url; ?&amp;gt;&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>dauble</name></author><category term="php" /><category term="php" /><summary type="html">For various projects I build, I always have three environments: local, staging and production. On my staging and production environments, I have HTTPS enabled, but to keep things simple, I never set up HTTPS on my local environment. A lot of sites I build require forms that redirect the user to a thank you page, once the data is sent and processed to Salesforce. The redirect though requires an absolute path, so I cannot use something like “/contact/thank-you/”. To accomplish this, I use this simple line in PHP to display the appropriate protocol, regardless of dev environment.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://davidauble.com/assets/images/posts/new-code.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://davidauble.com/assets/images/posts/new-code.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Fixing ‘Another git process seems to be running in this repository’ Error in Git</title><link href="https://davidauble.com/2018/10/23/fixing-another-git-process-seems-to-be-running-in-this-repository-error.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fixing ‘Another git process seems to be running in this repository’ Error in Git" /><published>2018-10-23T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-10-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://davidauble.com/2018/10/23/fixing-another-git-process-seems-to-be-running-in-this-repository-error</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://davidauble.com/2018/10/23/fixing-another-git-process-seems-to-be-running-in-this-repository-error.html">&lt;p&gt;I sometimes come across a unique error when using Git and always have to look up how to fix the error. It’s a simple error and can be replicated by stopping a Git command before it’s finished. Git in turn generates a “index.lock” file, which prevents you from adding any additional files to the commit. The error message I usually receive in full is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Another git process seems to be running in this repository, e.g. an editor opened by ‘git commit’. Please make sure all processes are terminated then try again. If it still fails, a git process may have crashed in this repository earlier: remove the file manually to continue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fix is simple: remove the “&lt;strong&gt;git.lock&lt;/strong&gt;” file in the “/.git/” directory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;rm -f .git/index.lock&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/38004148/another-git-process-seems-to-be-running-in-this-repository&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Credit: StackOverflow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>dauble</name></author><category term="git" /><category term="command line" /><summary type="html">I sometimes come across a unique error when using Git and always have to look up how to fix the error. It’s a simple error and can be replicated by stopping a Git command before it’s finished. Git in turn generates a “index.lock” file, which prevents you from adding any additional files to the commit. The error message I usually receive in full is:</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://davidauble.com/assets/images/posts/code.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://davidauble.com/assets/images/posts/code.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>